Friends, today in this video we will talk about
three such health insurance plans of
2025 which are needed by most of the people.
You have not been able to find the best health insurance plan till today.
What are the unique features in all three plans? What are the
similarities in all three plans?
So in this video I am going to tell you in full detail.
Friends, today in this video
we will talk about three such health insurance plans of
20225 which are needed by most of the people
and what are the features in these policies.
If you are looking for a health insurance plan
but have not been able to find the best health
insurance plan till today, then
this video is very important for you
because these three such
plans basically fulfill your complete
need, your complete basic need for
health insurance.
What are the unique features in all three plans? What are the
similarities in all three plans? Plus
what are the things that are not covered in all three plans
and when will they be covered? After how many
years can that happen? So in full detail
in this  In the video, I am going to tell you that these
three amazing plans of 2025,
if you purchase them in the coming time, then
you should at least not face any problem at the time of claim. So
watch the video till the end so that
you can at least take the best decision for health insurance.
Friends, I, Govinda Roy, have been working in this profession for more than
15 years and
we have got the claims of many people settled
and even today we are doing it, so
we are serving you in today's category also. If
you have any claim related issue, any
problem, any difficulty, then you can contact us on the
WhatsApp2 plan given above. We will do
a complete analysis of all the three plans in front of you.
Friends, if we talk about any
insurance company, then their in-card
claim ratio is basically how much
premium they have raised from the market
and how much premium they have given
to the people. Right,
this is called in-card claim ratio. So
if we talk about NIPA, if we talk about in-card
claim ratio, it is  59.01
HDFC Bank's card claim
ratio is 8.98 and IIC
Lord Health Insurance's card
claim ratio is
78.8. So, friends, first of all, if we
talk about the USP, that is, what is the unique selling point
in all three plans, then first of all, if
we talk about Niva Bappa's Aspire plan,
its biggest unique feature is
Lock the Clock, that is,
your premium will be frozen at the age at which you took the policy.
Suppose you
took your policy at the age of 35 and you did
not claim till the age of 60, then your premium will be the same, provided
if the government
increases the service tax, sorry, GST, etc., then it is a different matter,
but for the number of years you did
not pay the premium, your premium will be the same.
Next, the
biggest unique feature in the F plan is borderless, that is, if
you opt for a borderless rider, then
you can claim your policy even abroad.  If you have planned
surgery or any planned treatment, then
you can go abroad for it.
If you have taken borderless rider, then the
next benefit is maternity, that is,
they have a rider and that is Miracle
Benefit. If you have taken Miracle Benefit Rider, then in this the
company covers your entire life from adoption to survivance to maternity. So, the maternity is a
grid limit. If we
talk about Aspire plan, there are four variants in it.
Right, there are different limits in these four variants.
If you want that, then
I will put it in detail in the description box.
Right, the next benefit is
Booster Plus. That is, if you do not make a claim, then
your SAME SODE, suppose
your SAME SODE is of 10 lakhs, then the SAME SODE will be
reduced every year. Suppose
you have a policy of 10 lakhs, then if you do
not make a claim, it will become 20 lakhs. By doing this,
in 10 years your policy will become worth one
crore plus.  Along with this, your sum assured is
10 lakhs, that is, a policy of 1 crore 10 lakhs will be
made after 10 years. Next,
their one rider is Disease
Management i.e. DM Rider. If you
take DM Rider, then what will happen in it,
suppose you have diabetes or BP, then
your cover will start from day one. Now let's
move on to Optima Secure,
what is the unique selling point in Optima Secure, that is
2x coverage from day one, that is, if you
took a policy of 10 lakhs, or ADAC Ago in Optima Secure,
then your coverage will start from day one of
20 lakhs. There is another
benefit in this, that is Plus Benefit, that is, every
year your sum assured increases by 50%, that is, if it is
10 lakhs, then 5 lakhs will be added
next year and 5 lakhs, that means your policy will become of 20 lakhs, that is,
after 2 years,
if we say, then 20 plus your 10, that is, a
policy of 30 lakhs will be made. Next, after two years,
if you have taken
If you take Super Secure, then in Super Secure
you will basically get 3x coverage
right from day one and one unique selling
point if we talk about their ICR is
higher, which means their card claim ratio is
very good. If we talk about ADFC Ego's
next plan, it is IIC
Lombard's Elevate plan, which is the base plan, if
we talk about it, you
get a power booster, right, what will happen in the power booster,
your sum assured will increase every year, right,
your sum assured will increase every year,
if you take a power booster
rider, then this is their biggest unique
selling point, next is their civil
discount, that is, if your civil is good then you
also get a civil discount, right, the next benefit
in IIC Lombard's Elevate plan is
if you opt for a rider,
what will happen in it, you get unlimited sum assured coverage, that is, you get
sum assured for infinite time, in one plan, if
you take a rider for life time, if you have taken an
infinite rider, then your sum assured will be
unlimited  You get a room rate. Now friends, let
us talk about room rate.
If you look at any health insurance plan, the
biggest part is room rent, that is, suppose the
room rate. If we talk about any
health insurance, you
can say that from 20 to 30 or 40 percent,
your room rate is a part of your bill,
so the room rate plays a very big role.
Talking about room rate, here
we will see that there is no capping of room rate in Aspire plan, that is, if
you want,
you can take any room from single room to above like deluxe,
super deluxe, above like
VIP suite, there is
no restriction on room rate in it. Next, if we
talk about Optima Secure, there is no room rate capping in it also
and if we talk about
iLord, there is a room rate capping there, in
which you get a single private room,
so there is a room rate capping here. Now
friends, let us talk about bonus, that is,
if you purchase any health insurance plan, you will get a
bonus every  If the year
is added then if we talk about the black bonus grid,
in the Aspire plan it will be like suppose that there are
four variants in it, right like Gold
Plus, Platinum and Titanium, now let's
talk about Gold Plus, Diamond,
Platinum and Titanium, if
we talk about Gold Plus, then in Gold Plus it will be
5x, if you are from 45 to 35 years of age then your coverage will increase by 5x, if you are from 45 to 36 to 45 then your coverage will increase
by 3x, if it is 46 Plus then
your coverage will increase by 2x, right, so here let's
talk about the option of Gold Plus,
talk about Platinum and Titanium,
if we talk about 18 to 35 then it increases up to
10x, if you take Platinum and Titanium then
till the age of 35 your
sum assured increases 10x, that is, your sum assured increases by 10 times,
next if we talk about
36 to 45 then it increases up to 5x,
if it is 46 Plus then your coverage increases up to 3x,
talking about Black Bonus Optima Secure  If we talk about it, then there is a plus
benefit, like 5050 keeps increasing,
right addition of 50 on second year and
third year renewal on inception, as soon as
5050 increases, the notional bonus increases, if we talk about
it plan, then if we talk about notional bonus, then it will
increase every year by 20 per 100%, that is, 20-20, till
where will the maximum reach,
in the event plan of ICICI Lord, your right will reach
100% and now your claim also does
not get reduced,
friends, now let's move towards the next benefit, that is
refill benefit, right, so let's talk about refill benefit,
in Aspire plan, you get unlimited
number of times in a year for any illness, in
any illness, you will get the full claim,
same person gets the same illness and
unlimited times of restoration, that is, you
get refill benefit, some
call it refill, some call it restoration, some
call it recharge, so they call it by different names,
right  This is your unlimited
refill benefit. If we talk about the next
plan of HDFC Bank, Optimal Secure, then the
refill benefit will be once or equal
to the same amount for any illness. Same amount will be
your cover for any illness.
Right in Optimal Secure, if we
talk about the next plan of IIC Lord,
if in the Livet plan, there is unlimited number
of times in a year for any illness.
Unlimited times are there in this also and for any
illness cover is there in that also. Now let's talk about
friends, non-payable items are a very big
part. Suppose that any claim comes, then the
non-payable items which
are basically 10-15 charges in your bill,
you have to pay those charges yourself. If you have
not covered the non-payable items, like
consumer bills, then friends,
if we talk about non-payable items, in Aspire plan,
if you take Safeguard and Savard Plus,
Safeguard Plus, then your non-payable
Items which are covered through riders,
if we talk about Can be
Added Through Rider, there also
you can cover non-medical expenses through rider,
right OPD cover, right if we talk about OPD cover, then there
is OPD cover in Aspire plan, if you have
taken wellness rider, well consult rider, you
get OPD benefit in which the
limit is around 20000 per year,
if we talk about ADFC Air Plan,
Optima Well Being Rider, Edge Rider is available
there too, if you take Optima Well Rider,
right then you get Edge OPD cover there too,
right so now if you see,
you can take OPD cover in IIC Lumbard also
through rider, in all three
you can take OPD cover through rider if you want,
emergency road ambulance,
friends, if we talk about
covered edge in NIBA Aspire plan, actual up to the same
short road ambulance which is up to the same
amount, that will be
covered edge in ADFC plan  Actual up to the same
level, in this also there is same level cover and in that
too if you have IC load, in all the three, your
road ambulance is the complete actual level cover.
Emergency air ambulance is a very big part.
Today, every company has started providing it in the market. If we
talk about emergency air ambulance, then
you have the actual level cover in NIBA.
Here, if we talk about AC in which there is a
capping of up to 5 lakhs, right and can be added through
rider. If you want,
you can add it in IC load through rider.
If we talk about complimentary wellness, then
your complimentary
wellness test is available in all the three. If you
want to do a complimentary wellness test, then
that is also available. The
option is available in all the three. Friends, if you talk about
any plan, then there is no discount in one year.
In all the three plans, if you
want, then you would get a discount in the premium if you take it for 2 years or 3 years.
That
discount is available in all the three. Now
friends, let's talk about pre and post hospitalization.
Post hospitalization
in Aspire plan, pre hospitalization
is 60 days and post is 180 days, so
in all three, in two plans like Aspire and
HDFC Arg, it is 60 and 180 days,
if we talk about 11 plan, then it is 90 days, 90
and 180 days, right pre and post
means the expenses before going to the hospital, the expenses
after being discharged from the hospital, basically the company
covers that, which you
can reimburse, now friends, the next
part is e-consultation, that is,
if you want to do any e-consultation, then
you can do e-consultation with the doctor on their panel,
unlimited e-consultation is available in Aspire plan,
second medical opinion once a year,
you can also take second medical opinion, let me
talk about ADFC Optima Secure for 51
listed critical illnesses,
if you have any complaint regarding 51 listed critical illnesses, then
you can take e-consultation in it.
Unlimited EE consultation
is available in Lord. Another benefit that every
company is offering these days is the wellness
benefit. This means that if you stay healthy,
count your steps, run, go to the gym, and
stay healthy, you get a discount from the
company, which
can also be called a reward point. At the time of renewal,
you get a premium discount. You have to
download an application from whichever company you are.
You have to count your steps. According to
whatever reading is shown in it,
you can avail a discount of up to 30 steps within a year.
If we talk about the NIFER plan, then
that thing is not available in ADFC Ergo.
And if we talk about ICICI
Lord, in which you can avail a discount of up to 20 steps.
Friends, if we talk about
copayment, then there is
no copayment in Aspire and ADFC Ergo. If
you want to add a copayment, you
can add it through a rider.
Right Deduct Now Deduct is available in ICICI Lord's Event Plan.  If we
talk about it, then you can take deduction here.
I do not suggest deduction.
If you take deduction then your premium will be
cheaper. Deductible means
that if you take deduction of Rs. 20,000, suppose you
take deduction of Rs. 50,000, or Rs. 1 lakh, then it
means that if a claim comes,
you will have to pay up to that amount. After that
amount, the company will pay. So, it is
not necessary to apply deduction to reduce the premium a little, otherwise it may cost
you more than the cost. But if
you are running a corporate policy, then if
you want to reduce the premium in that, then
you can take deduction. Friends,
if we purchase any plan, then there is
some specific waiting
period here. Basically, let's
talk about specific waiting period, like cataract,
hernia, stone, piles,
hysterectomy, all these
diseases are basically for 24 months.  The cover is
covered after 24 months. The surgeries which are not life-threatening,
right? The surgeries which
can be avoided, those surgeries are called
specific illnesses. For example, if there is an ENT problem, then it
comes under specific illness,
so that will be covered after 24 months in both these
three plans. The specific illness is covered after the same 24 months in all the three plans.
Right, PD waiting period. Or if
we talk about the pre-
assisted
rule, in that, the
pre-assisted disease is covered for 3 years. If
we talk about HDAC Optimal Secur,
which has 3 years and IIC Lord's
Livet plan, which has 3 years of
coverage, that
means whether your policy is covered worldwide
or not. If you have a rider in the air plan
which is called Borderless Rider, if you
take it, then your policy can work even in foreign countries, that is,
you can go and get planning
surgery done, etc.
You can also get planning treatment done if you have
taken Borderless Rider.  Which is
available in Optimus Secure in Ni's Affer Plan.
Now ADAC Secure Global and Global
Plus, if you are a rider, you can also opt for
ADAC Er Go which
is available in Optimal Secure. If we talk about IIC
Lord Event Plan, that thing is not available in
friends, if there is any plan then there is
some entry age criteria in it.
Basically, if we talk about entry age,
in Niba Apfer Plan, if any person is between 18 to 65 years then he can
enter.
In this plan, if a child is in it, then a
child of 91 days can enter. The maximum
stay is 30 years. Plus, if you want a
dependent child, then he can carry on even after that.
If we talk about ADAC Ag
Optima Secure, if
any person is 18 years old then he can enter in it. There is
no limit on maximum entry.
In ADAC Age, the age of the child is from 91 days to
25 years. The age of the child in this policy is
91 days.  You can enter and
stay in this policy for a maximum of 25 years.
Next, if we talk about IC Lombard's
Elevate plan, in which the age of the child is 18 and the maximum age is
125 years. The
right of the child is between 91 to 30 years.
Talking about sum assured, friends, that is sum
assured, in which
you can take a sum assured from Rs 3 lakh to Rs 1 crore
in Nipa Aspire plan. Next, if we talk about
hdfcfund.com Optimal Secure plan, next,
if we talk about IC Lombard, in
which you can opt for a sum assured from Rs 5 lakh to unlimited.
Friends, we have just understood the plan, so it is
important for us to see the premium as well whether our
pocket allows it or not. So,
if we have done a calculation in the plan, if we
talk about Zone One, that is, the cities of Zone One, then there is a
coverage of Rs 10 lakh, in which
if we talk about a 31-year-old
person, right, if suppose his wife
Wife's age is 28 years plus child who
is a 1 year old child like suppose we have taken the
example of a 1 year old child,
right then 2+1 means husband wife and one
child, right a policy of 10 lakhs in which if
we talk about Safeguard Plus like we have
covered the consumer also, so if we talk about the
premium of Zone One here, if we talk about the
App plan, the premium is 27710, the premium is
of hdfc0000090 and
with claim protector, if we talk about IIC
Lord Elevate plan in which the
premium is ₹1686, in IIC Lord's Elevate
plan, but here if I
talk to you in comparison, where there is capping of room rate,
basically you get to see the premium a little cheaper there
because room rent is a very big part,
so if we talk about such a lord here, then there is
capping of room rate but upa and
complete  You get a claim and there is no
complaint about the room rent after going there, there is no problem,
so I have compared all the three plans,
you must have noted down each point,
which points did you like in each plan, what
things did you find
negative, so you
must go and comment in the comments, if you want to
buy one of these plans, then which plan
can you buy, just please comment
which plan you like so that
others also know that brother, you have
chosen this plan, is the plan suitable for you, is it
suitable for others or
not, right, you must
comment in the comment box, which plan are you
going to buy, right, if you have
any other issue related to the plan, you have any
queries, then you can contact us
through WhatsApp2, if you want to buy the best plan, then
you can contact our team,
our team will search for the best plan
from the market, compare it for you and find the
cheapest plan for you,
along with the cheapest benefit, where you can also
go to the claim  After this, at least you will
not get any complaint. Friends, if you are a health
insurance agent or a distributor
of life insurance or mutual funds,
but you are
not taking health insurance seriously,
then you can associate with us by taking up a health insurance agency and handling it.
Friends, if you
want to make a career by taking up a health insurance agency, then you
can contact us.
We recruit agents on an all-India basis.
We train agents and give
them the best guidance and a
successful career as an
agent.
So, if you
want to be successful and want to take up a health insurance
agency, then you can contact us.
Our team will help you. You will get the best
guidance and support from me too,
so that
you can do the best work in your health insurance career
and earn lakhs of rupees from
here. I am an MDT HB
advisor and have been
working in the market for more than 15 years.
I have settled claims for many people.  Yes,
in today's date we are serving you people,
so our practical experience is
mine, which we
will share with you, plus you will
get guidance accordingly
so that you can become a successful one at least, so
what are you waiting for, you also call and our
team will support you, friends, on which
topic should I make the next video, you must
comment me so that
I can prepare the next video in a very good manner and
bring it in front of you,
friends, it takes a lot of hard work to make a video, so
my request is that if you like the video, then
you must  Please like this and share
this video with your family and friends
so that they too can get knowledge
related to health insurance. If you have
visited the channel for the first time and have
not subscribed, then please subscribe
so that in the coming time
I will bring innovative content, by
watching them you can get a great
experience and knowledge,
right, thank you so much, see you
in the next video, till then bye bye
Vande Mataram.